<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ramblings</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ramblings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 21:15:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello folks, welcome to my blog. I&amp;rsquo;m a software engineer, avid reader and yoga lover.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seaching For Fun With fd</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/fd-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 21:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/fd-basics/</guid>
      <description>fd is a blazing fast (I know, I know 😉) replacement for the in-built find command. I&amp;rsquo;ve been having a lot of fun incorporating it as part of my workflow so figured out I should at least blog about its basics.&#xA;The official readme details out all the possible flags/options for using the tool but I&amp;rsquo;ve reiterated them here for my personal quick reference, to internalise the syntax and with the hope that someone else might find it useful.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction To GNU Screen</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/an-introduction-to-gnu-screen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 12:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/an-introduction-to-gnu-screen/</guid>
      <description>I personally believe that using a terminal multiplexer is a must for anyone who spends a non-trivial amount working on remote *nix servers. This post is a gentle introduction to GNU screen but I would like to take a short detour and explain why they are useful.&#xA;Why use a terminal multiplexer? Some of the most obvious advantages being:&#xA;Ability to have a saved session for your work Cutting down the number of terminal windows you have to open Let&amp;rsquo;s discuss a usecase wherein you are logged on to your Edge/Gateway node and would like to monitor your Spark jobs, your HBase service and at the same time query Impala tables.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Negative look-behind trap -- regex</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/the-negative-lookbehind-trap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2017 12:00:00 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/the-negative-lookbehind-trap/</guid>
      <description>A request was made in this Daniweb thread to split a string based on punctuations and whitespaces but with a twist. The splitting should make exceptions/allowances for special cases.&#xA;For e.g. let&amp;rsquo;s say we are splitting on . (the dot character). Our splitting should keep titles like Mrs. and Mr. intact. What does this mean? Let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at it with an example (for those wondering, the code snippets are in Python programming language):</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
